Register of the Stanislaw Mikolajczyk Papers, 1899-1966
Hoover Institution Archives
- AUDIO-VISUAL FILE, 1936-1966
  - Photographs, 1936-1963
    - 1 print depicting Franklin D. Roosevelt, with a personal dedication for Stanislaw Mikolajczyk, n.d. (Folder 46)
    - 1 print depicting Cardinal Sapieha, n.d. (Folder 47)
    - 3 prints depicting Wladyslaw Sikorski during his trip to the Soviet Union, 1941 (Folder 48)
    - 5 prints depicting members of Wladyslaw Sikorski's government, 1942? (Folder 49)
    - 1 print depicting Wladyslaw Sikorski, n.d. (Folder 50)
    - 2 prints depicting Wladyslaw Sikorski and Cazalet, 1943 (Folder 51)
    - 6 prints depicting General Wladyslaw Sikorski inspecting Polish troops in France, 1939 (Folder 52)
    - 1 print depicting General Wladyslaw Sikorski and Winston Churchill inspecting Polish troops in Scotland, 1942? (Folder 53)
    - 1 print depicting General Wladyslaw Sikorski during the ceremony of the Polish Airforce flag presentation, 1942? (Folder 54)
    - 1 print depicting Wladyslaw Sikorski in Beirut, 1943 June (Folder 55)
    - 1 print depcting the ORP Orkan departing from Gibraltar with Wladyslaw Sikorski's body, 1943 July (Folder 56)
    - 16 prints depicting Arciszewski Tomasz, Anthony Eden, Wladyslaw Raczkiewicz, Helena Sikorska, and Kazimierz Sosnkowski participating in the first anniversary ceremony of Wladyslaw Sikorski's death, London, 1944 (Folder 57)
    - 2 prints depicting the signing of the Polish-Soviet agreement by Wladyslaw Sikorski and Joseph Stalin, 1941 (Folder 58)
    - 10 prints depicting ceremonies in Poland on the anniversary of Wincenty Witos's death, 1965 (Folder 59)
    - 4 prints depicting religious ceremonies in Poland, with participation of Cardinal Stefan Wyszynski and Karol Wojtyla?, 1960s (Folder 60)
    - 1 print depicting members of the Polskie Stronnictwo Ludowe at a socio-political training in Bnin, Poland, 1936 (Box 210, Folder 1)
    - 1 print depicting members of Polskie Stronnictwo Ludowe in Teheran, 1943 (Folder 2)
    - 7 prints depicting street demonstrations in Warsaw in front of the United States Embassy in protest against attacks on Polskie Stronnictwo Ludowe, 1946? (Folder 3)
    - 3 prints depicting the celebration of Peasant Holiday in Chicago by members of Polskie Stronnictwo Ludowe, 1949 (Folder 4)
    - 5 prints depicting a gathering of members of Polskie Stronnictwo Ludowe in Washington in front of the Kosciuszko monument, 1949 (Folder 5)
    - 14 prints depicting a meeting of Polskie Stronnictwo Ludowe in the United States, 1948 (Folder 6)
    - 15 prints depicting a meeting of Rada Naczelna, NKW, in the 1950s (Folder 7)
    - 3 prints depicting May 3rd street celebrations of Polskie Stronnictwo Ludowe members in Saint- Etienne, France, 1950-1951 (Folder 8)
    - 54 prints depicting the Polskie Stronnictwo Ludowe Congress in Paris, 1955 (Folder 9)
    - 60 prints depicting the Polskie Stronnictwo Ludowe Congress in Paris, 1955 (Folder 10)
    - 15 prints depicting the Polskie Stronnictwo Ludowe Congress in Paris, 1955 (Folder 11)
    - 56 print depicting Polskie Stronnictwo Ludowe meetings in the United States and Canada, 1955 and 1950s (Folder 12)
    - 10 prints depicting Polskie Stronnictwo Ludowe members in Liege, Belgium, 1957 (Folder 13)
    - 16 prints depicting a Polskie Stronnictwo Ludowe congress in Paris, 1957 (Folder 14)
    - 5 prints depicting a Polskie Stronnictwo Ludowe meeting in France?, 1957 or 1958? (Folder 15)
    - 9 prints depicting Polskie Stronnictwo Ludowe Peasant Holiday celebrations in Sudbury, Canada, 1958 (Folder 16)
    - 9 prints depicting Polskie Stronnictwo Ludowe members in Belgium, 1958 (Folder 17)
    - 36 prints depicting Polskie Stronnictwo Ludowe celebrations of Peasant Holiday in the United States, late 1950s (Folder 18)
    - 46 prints depicting members of a Polskie Stronnictwo Ludowe congress, Paris, 1955 (Folder 19)
    - 6 prints depicting Polskie Stronnictwo Ludowe members in Sweden, 1959 (Folder 20)
    - 2 prints depicting members of Polskie Stronnictwo Ludowe celebrating Peasant Holiday, United States, 1960 (Folder 21)
    - 28 prints depicting Polskie Stronnictwo Ludowe Congress in Paris, France, 1961 (Folder 22)
    - 2 prints depicting Polskie Stronnictwo Ludowe members in the Netherlands, 1962 (Folder 23)
    - 3 prints depicting Polskie Stronnictwo Ludowe members in Belgium, 1962 (Folder 24)
    - 11 prints depicting Polskie Stronnictwo Ludowe members in Great Britain, 1962 (Folder 25)
    - 18 prints depicting Polskie Stronnictwo Ludowe celebrations of Peasant Holiday in Chicago, 1963 (Folder 26)
    - 38 prints depicting activities of Polskie Stronnictwo Ludowe in Chicago in celebrations of Peasant Holiday and the anniversary of General Wladyslaw Sikorski's death, 1963 (Folder 27)
    - 22 prints depicting Polskie Stronictwo Ludowe in Chicago in celebration of Peasant Holiday, Chicago, 1963 (Folder 28)
    - 10 prints depicting Polskie Stronnictwo Ludowe in Manchester, England, in seminar and commemoration of Wincenty Witos, 1963 (Folder 29)
    - 5 prints depicting Polskie Stronnictwo Ludowe members in Germany, early 1960s (Folder 30)
    - 48 prints depicting the Polskie Stronnictwo Ludowe Congress in Paris, France, 1963 (Box 211, Folder 1)
    - 41 prints depicting the Polskie Stronnictwo Ludowe Congress in Paris, France, 1963 (Folder 2)
    - 24 prints depicting the Polskie Stronnictwo Ludowe Congress in Paris, France, 1963 (Folder 3)
    - 40 prints depicting the Polskie Stronnictwo Ludowe Congress in Paris, France, 1963 (Folder 4)
    - 22 prints depicting members of the Stowarzyszenie Przyjaciol Wsi Polskiej w Ameryce in Chicago, 1950s (Folder 5)
    - 4 prints depicting the banner of Stowarzyszenie Przyjaciol Wsi Polskiej, Salem, Oregon, 1953 (Folder 6)
    - 38 prints depicting the Zwiazek Przyjaciol Wsi Polskiej Congress, Salem, Oregon, 1953 (Folder 7)
    - 10 prints depicting members of Zwiazek Przyjaciol Wsi Polskiej celebrating the Poznan Uprising anniversary, 1958 (Folder 8)
    - 2 prints depicting a meeting of East European peasant leaders in the United States, early 1960s (Folder 9)
    - 15 prints depicting the Wici summer camp in France, 1948 (Folder 10)
    - 42 prints depicting the Wici summer camp in France, 1948 (Folder 11)
    - 24 prints depicting participants of the Rural Catholic Congress, Santiago, Chile, 1957 (Folder 12)
    - 2 prints depicting participants of the European Confederation of Agriculture Congress, Vienna, 1958 (Folder 13)
    - 28 prints depicting the Assembly of Captive European Nations Congress, Paris, 1958 (Folder 14)
    - 17 prints depicting participants of the European Confederation of Agriculture Congress, Palermo, Italy, 1959 (Folder 15)
    - 3 prints depicting participants of the European Confederation of Agriculture Congress, Cannes, France, 1963 (Folder 16)
    - 4 prints depicting the International Peasant Union Congress in Paris, 1956 (Box 212, Folder 1)
    - 56 prints depicting the International Peasant Union Congress in Paris, 1956 (Folder 2)
    - 32 prints depicting the International Peasant Union Congress in Paris, 1956 (Folder 3)
    - 30 prints depicting the International Peasant Union Forum in Brussels, 1958 (Folder 4)
    - 83 prints depicting the International Peasant Union Congress in Washington, D.C., 1959 (Folder 5)
    - 19 prints depicting the International Peasant Union Congress in Madrid, 1962 (Folder 6)
    - 2 prints depicting the International Peasant Union Congress in Cannes, France, 1963 (Folder 7)
    - 14 prints depicting the International Peasant Union Congress in Cannes, France, 1963 (Folder 8)
    - 12 prints depicting underground resistance groups Uderzenie and Wschod, early 1940s (Folder 9)
    - 1 print depicting the sign of Polska Walczaca, n.d. (Folder 10)
    - 7 prints depicting the Polish colony in Budapest, 1942-1943 (Folder 11)
    - 1 print depicting the residence of the Polish State Council in London, 1943 (Folder 12)
    - 11 prints depicting Polish armed forces in Europe and the Soviet Union, 1943-1944 (Folder 13)
    - 6 prints depicting Polish youth during World War II (Folder 14)
    - 4 prints depicting demonstrations in New York against persecution of Jews under German occupation, 1944? (Folder 15)
    - 4 prints depicting anti-communist street demonstrations in Warsaw, 1946? (Folder 16)
    - 6 prints depicting destruction of Wawolnica village, 1946 (Folder 17)
    - 9 prints depicting illustrations used in Stanislaw Mikolajczyk's Rape of Poland, 1948 (Folder 18)
    - 1 print depicting a flyer of Polish Varieties radio program in Buffalo, New York, 1948 (Folder 19)
    - 1 print depicting participants at the Mid-Century World Outlook Conference, Greenville, 1950? (Folder 20)
    - 2 prints depicting members of the Polish National Committee in session, 1952 (Folder 21)
    - 1 print depicting street demonstration of solidarity with Hungary in Olsztyn, Poland, 1956 (Folder 22)
    - 10 prints depicting the Soviet agricultural exhibit in Brussels, 1958 (Folder 23)
    - 4 prints depicting unidentified people, n.d. (Folder 24)
  - Photograph albums
    - Stanislaw Mikolajczyk as Prime Minister, from the day of his nomination in 1943, and members of his government, 1943-1944; ceremonies with Mrs. Kazalet-Keirr, the Regent of Iraq, Mr. Cadogan, Mr. Sinclair, Lord Elgin, Mr. Addinsel; and the Polish Parachute Brigade (Box 213, Folder 1)
    - Stanislaw Mikolajczyk's trip to Japan, 1955 (Folder 2)
    - Polish Army in France, 1939-1940 (Box 214, Folder 1)
    - General Wladyslaw Sikorski and his government in France and England, 1939-1940; his trip to England, and inspection of Polish troops; and various diplomatic ceremonies with participation of Stanislaw Mikolajczyk and Wladyslaw Raczkiewicz (Folder 2)
    - Polskie Stronnictwo Ludowe and Zwiazek Przyjaciol Wsi Polskiej celebrations in the United States, 1958-1959 (Box 215, Folder 1)
    - Sikorski's and Mikolajczyk's trip to the United States, 1941; Ignacy Paderewski; meetings with Polish-Americans and American government officials (Folder 2)
- OVERSIZE FILE, 1947.
  - Carbon matrix of Stanislaw Mikolajczyk's speech at the Polish Parliament, 1947 June 23 (Box 216)